<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-08-03T10:34:11+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">MonkatForty</title><subtitle>My personal blog. </subtitle><author><name>Dipannita</name><email>monkatforty@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Hemis Monastery of Ladakh and the Hemis Festival</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/hemis-monatery-of-ladakh-and-the-hemis-festival/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hemis Monastery of Ladakh and the Hemis Festival" /><published>2022-07-06T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2022-07-06T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/hemis-monatery-of-ladakh-and-the-hemis-festival</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/hemis-monatery-of-ladakh-and-the-hemis-festival/"><![CDATA[<p>Hemis Monatery of Ladakh is the largest and the richest monastery of the Ladakh region. 45 milometers from Leh, stands this famous gompa or monastery at the Hemis Village, near the Hemis National Park where the endangered snow leopards are found. This 40 kilometres drive is something that remains etched in the memory for a very long time. This 11th century monastery of Drukpa Kagyu lineage (Red Hat Sect of Buddhism) was restored in 1672 AD by Taktsang Respa Ngawang Gyatso under the patronage of the Ladakhi King, Sengge Namgyal. A golden Buddha seated on a hill top overlooks the vast expanse of the valley and the sprawling monastery. This Himalayan Tibetan-Buddhist Monastery, perched at an altitude of 12000 feet is globally famous for the Hemis Festival in June-July. In 2022, i.e.,this year the dates are 8th and 9th of July.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6957.jpg" title="Drive from Hemis to Leh">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6957.jpg" alt="Drive from Hemis to Leh" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6975.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6975.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6959.jpg" title="Hemis">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6959.jpg" alt="Hemis" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6963.jpg" title="Entrance to the Courtyard">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6963.jpg" alt="Entrance to the courtyard" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6976.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6976.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6965.jpg" title="Hemis Gompa">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6965.jpg" alt="Hemis Gompa" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6964.jpg" title="Courtyard">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6964.jpg" alt="Courtyard" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6977.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6977.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6958.jpg" title="Road to Hemis">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6958.jpg" alt="Road to Hemis" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="things-to-see-at-hemis-monastery-of-ladakh">Things to See at Hemis Monastery of Ladakh:</h2>

<p>Hemis Monastery of Ladakh has a typical Tibetan architecture where ample use of mud, wood and stones for construction is observed. Walls of the gompa have detailed murals of Tibetan gods and goddesses and other sacred symbols significant to Tibetan Tantric Buddhism. ‘Wheel of Life’ is an important painting. These paintings are extremely colourful and the colourful prayer flags compliment them and there are numerous prayer wheels of various sizes too. The vivid colours look beautiful in contrast to the rugged mountains or landscape around. A large courtyard is at the center and to its right from the entrance is Tshogs-khang, the main temple of the Buddha housing a huge gilded blue haired idol of Sakyamuni Buddha. The Du-Khang, another part of the temple, is the main Assembly Hall with the throne of the Rinpoche and the seats for the lamas (monks). There is temple dedicated to Guru Padmasambhaba and the founder of the Hemis Monastery of Ladakh. The Hemis Museum, the mural gallery and a souvenir shop are must visit sites within the gompa. The museum exhibits items, sculptures, paintings, manuscripts and thangkas which are as old as thousand years. The mural gallery has wall paintings done with stone and natural dyes. Do not miss the roof top because the panoramic view from the terrace is breath taking. Try out Tibetan dishes at the café just outside the monastery; they are delicious. The visiting time is 8 am to 6 pm and 1 pm-2 pm is lunch hour. Ticket cost per person for entry is Rs.50 and it includes a visit to the museum as well.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6969.jpg" title="Staircase to the entrance/courtyard">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6969.jpg" alt="Staircase to the entrance/courtyard" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6968.jpg" title="view from the terrace">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6968.jpg" alt="view from the terrace" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6966.jpg" title="Guru Padmasambhava">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6966.jpg" alt="Guru Padmasambhava" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6970.jpg" title="A Monk with cymbals at the mural gallery">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6970.jpg" alt="A Monk with cymbals at the mural gallery" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6961.jpg" title="Lama's stay">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6961.jpg" alt="Lama's stay" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6967.jpg" title="Terrace">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6967.jpg" alt="Terrace" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6971.jpg" title="Hemis Gompa courtyard">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6971.jpg" alt="Hemis Gompa courtyard" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6972.jpg" title="Prayer wheel">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6972.jpg" alt="Prayer wheel" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="hemis-festival-at-hemis-monastery-of-ladakh">Hemis Festival at Hemis Monastery of Ladakh</h2>

<p>Hemis Monastery of Ladakh boasts of the famous Hemis Festival which takes place in June or July (10th and 11th day of the fifth month of Tibetan Lunar calendar), to commemorate the birth anniversary of Guru Padmasambhava or Rinpoche. The festival is unique and colourful and is celebrated with tremendous devotion and spiritual fervor. The festival begins with rituals are performed by the chief monk in association with other monks. A 350 years old huge (20 feet) thangka with image of Guru Rinpoche is hung from top for the devotees. Mask dances called Chham, performed by the monks at the courtyard make the festival so distinctive and special. The dances mostly imply ‘the holy’ driving away ‘the unholy’. Ritualistic chants, beating of drums, clashing of cymbals and wailing of conchs and Tibetan horn pipes (dughchen-trumpets) create a magical environment of festivity and transcendental energy.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisthird/silk.jpg" title="Thangka of Guru Padmasambhava">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisthird/silk.jpg" alt="Thangka of Guru Padmasambhava" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisthird/Md2.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisthird/Md2.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisthird/Hemis-Festival_1.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisthird/Hemis-Festival_1.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisthird/festival.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisthird/festival.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisthird/trumpets-1.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisthird/trumpets-1.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="the-mask-dances-of-hemis-festival">The Mask Dances of Hemis Festival</h2>

<p>The mask dances of Hemis Festival is the chief attraction and follow a sequence with each dance representing a story. The audience at Hemis Monastery of Ladakh is not restricted to Buddhists only. From all across the globe keen visitors come to attend the festival; devotees, travelers, photographers and film makers.</p>

<ul>
  <li>The series of dances begin with the dance of the 4 Gomas or Gatekeepers who wear vibrant brocade dresses and huge wooden masks with skulls on top. Their dance is meant to bind the evil spirits so that they cannot escape.</li>
  <li>Next come the 12 Zhings or Dharmapalas, the guardians of the truth who dance to keep the teachings of the Buddha protected from impurities.</li>
  <li>The dance of the 5 Chemchog Heruka follows next. They represent the fierce form of Guru Rinpoche/ Padmasambhava who eliminates evil with wrath and liberate the land from darkness.</li>
  <li>Then follows the dance of the 4 Lords of the Graveyards who celebrate the death of immorality. They rejoice to celebrate the triumph of good over evil. They wear large wooden masks which look like skulls and their attires also have skeleton woven on them.</li>
  <li>The dance festival ends with the Black Hat Dance by 13 monks. They close the dance with a ritual of protecting the sacred arena such that evil can’t pervade.</li>
</ul>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfourth/mask-dance-2.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfourth/mask-dance-2.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfourth/MD.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfourth/MD.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfourth/festival-ladakh.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfourth/festival-ladakh.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfourth/mask-dance.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfourth/mask-dance.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="takeaways-from-the-hemis-festival-andor-hemis-monastery">Takeaways from the Hemis Festival and/or Hemis Monastery</h2>

<p>The pivotal point across which the majestic Hemis Monastery of Ladakh and the iconic Hemis Festival revolve is the idea of victory of good over evil. Whether we experience the enthusiasm and energy of the festival or the tranquility and solitude of the monastery during other times, we come out a changed person; a person who can retrospect, differentiate and finally choose between what is right and what is wrong. Buddha said, “By oneself, indeed, is evil done; by oneself is one defiled. By oneself is evil left undone; by oneself, indeed, is one purified. Purity and impurity depend on oneself. No one purifies another.”</p>

<figure class=" ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfive/IMG_6962-1.jpg" title="Monks Rehearsing for The Hemis Festival Mask Dance">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfive/IMG_6962-1.jpg" alt="Monks Rehearsing for The Hemis Festival Mask Dance" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>]]></content><author><name>Dipannita</name><email>monkatforty@gmail.com</email></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Festival" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Excerpt for a festival]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Rathas/Chariots of Jagannath’s Chariot Parade/ Ratha Yatra at Puri</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/ratha-yatra-at-puri/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Rathas/Chariots of Jagannath’s Chariot Parade/ Ratha Yatra at Puri" /><published>2022-07-01T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2022-07-01T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/ratha-yatra-at-puri</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/ratha-yatra-at-puri/"><![CDATA[<p>The word ‘Juggernaut’, meaning a large and heavy vehicle and also a huge, powerful, and overwhelming force, was coined in by the British when they saw the Chariot Parade or Rath Yatra at Puri, a beach town in Odisha. This festival is unfathomably grand, with millions of devotees visiting Puri from all across the globe. ‘Yatra’ means pilgrimage; during Ratha Yatra pilgrims flood in to see the travelling god. Lord Jagannath travels every year with his sister, Subhadra, and brother, Balabhadra, to his aunt’s house at the neighbouring Gundicha Temple, 3 kms from their residence, the famous Jagannath Temple of Puri. Each deity has their respective chariots which are brightly coloured and majestic. These chariots are built every year and the process starts from more than 2 months before the festival. This is a festival where faith, mythology, legends, craftsmanship, art and culture merge.</p>

<figure class="half ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrafirst/ratha1.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrafirst/ratha1.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrafirst/ratha2.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrafirst/ratha2.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="wood-for-chariot-making-of-rath-yatra-at-puri">Wood for Chariot Making of Rath Yatra at Puri</h2>

<p>Every year the Odisha government supplies the wood for the chariots to the temple authorities free of cost. More than 1000 logs of of Phasi, Dhaura (<em>Anogeissus latifolia</em>), Asan (<em>Terminalia elliptica</em>) and Simal (<em>Bombax ceiba</em>), along with a few other trees (12 species) are majorly used for the construction of chariots of Jagannath, Balabhadra and Subhadra every year. This year loads of logs are donated to the temple committee by private land owners of Nayagarh and Khordha Districts of Odisha.</p>

<p>After the festival of Ratha Yatra at Puri, the chariots are dismantled and the wood goes to the temple’s mega kitchen, to be used as firewood to cook <em>prasad</em> for the deities. The mega kitchen provides Prasad/bhog to at least 30,000 devotees daily. 6 times 56 types of bhog is offered to Lord Jagannath and there are more than 500 cooks for that.</p>

<figure class="half ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrasecond/wood1.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrasecond/wood1.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrasecond/wood2.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrasecond/wood2.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="the-world-famous-chariots-of-puri">The World Famous Chariots of Puri</h2>

<p>Three chariots each for the three deities are constructed every year in the same traditional pattern, without any written documented instructions. Instructions have been handed over orally for generations to the carpenters, blacksmiths, artisans, craftsmen, painters and tailors. These chariots are more than 40 feet high and the artisans begin with their gigantic wheels with a diameter of 7 feet. A total of 42 wheels are constructed. The rathas are <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deula">deula</a>-shaped, inspired by the Odisha temple architecture. Their and frames have paintings and carvings inspired by ancient Odisha Temple art and architecture too. They are also covered with vibrant fabrics with intricate Odisha embroideries. In front of the chariots are wooden statues of charioteers and horses and the devotees pull the holy ropes tied to the chariots. They are literally no ordinary ropes. Each rope is 220 feet long and has a circumference of 8 inches. Odisha Cooperative Coir Corporation (OCCC) supplies these ropes to the Shree Jagannath Temple Administration (SJTA). The astonishing fact about chariots of Ratha Yatra at Puri is that every element of each chariot is specific to that particular chariot only.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot1.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot1.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot2.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot2.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot3.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot3.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot4.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot4.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot5.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot5.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot6.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot6.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot7.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot7.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot8.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot8.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot9.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot9.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot10.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot10.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot11.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot11.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
    <figcaption>The Making of the Chariots
</figcaption>
  
</figure>

<h2 id="nandighosha-the-chariot-of-lord-jagannath">Nandighosha, the Chariot of Lord Jagannath</h2>

<p>Nandighosha, the Ratha of Lord Jagannath is also called Garudadhwaja and/or Kapidhwaja. It is almost 45 feet high and 35 feet wide, covered in vibrant red and yellow fabrics. The flag on top is called Trailakyamohini. The deity of Lord Jagannath is brought out of the temple by the priests with a left to right swing. The Jagannath ratha has 16 wheels. Garuda is the guard and Daruka is the charioteer and there are 4 white horses of the chariot; Sankha, Balahaka, Suweta and Haridashwa. Nandighosha’s rope is called Sankhachuda Naguni. The 9 deities carved on the ratha are Varaha, Gobardhana, Gopi Krishna, Nrishingha, Rama, Narayana, Trivikrama, Hanuman and Rudra. The face of the chariot is called Nandi Mukha and weapons associated with this particular chariot are Sankha and Chakra, those of Lord Vishnu. Vishnu is also worshiped as Lord Jagannath, the Lord of the Universe and Puri Dham is one of the Char Dhams. Understanding Ratha Yatra at Puri is incomplete without detailed knowledge of the rathas where every element of design is distinct and specific to each ratha.</p>

<figure class="half ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrafourth/nandighosha1.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrafourth/nandighosha1.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrafourth/nandighosha2.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrafourth/nandighosha2.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="padmadhwaja-the-chariot-of-lord-jagannaths-sister-subhadra">Padmadhwaja, the Chariot of Lord Jagannath’s Sister, Subhadra</h2>

<p>Subhadra’s Ratha is also called Darpadalana and/or Devadalana and is almost 42 feet high and 31 feet wide, covered in vibrant red and black fabrics. The flag on top is called Nadambika. The deity of Subhadra is brought out of the temple by the priests with out swinging, almost in a sleeping position.This ratha has 12 wheels. Jayadurga is the guard and Arjuna is the charioteer and there are 4 brown horses of the chariot; Rochika, Mochika, Jita and Aparajita. The rope of this Ratha is called Swarnachuda Naguni. 9 female deities are carved on the ratha; Chandi, Chamunda, Ugra Tara, Vana Durga, Shuli Durga, Varahi, Shyama Kali, Mangala and Vimala. Subhadra’s ratha stands in between the rathas of her brothers during Ratha Yatra at Puri. The face of the chariot is known as Bhakti Sumedha and Padma and Kalhar are the associated weapons.</p>

<figure class="half ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrafifth/subhadras1.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrafifth/subhadras1.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrafifth/subhadras2.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrafifth/subhadras2.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="taladhwaja-the-chariot-of-lord-jagannaths-brother-balabhadra">Taladhwaja, the Chariot of Lord Jagannath’s Brother, Balabhadra</h2>

<p>Balabhadra’s Ratha is called Taladhwaja and is almost 43 feet tall and 33 feet wide, covered in vibrant red and green fabrics with Unnani, the flag on. The deity of Balabhadra is brought out of the temple by the priests with a front to back swing.This ratha has 14 wheels. Basudev is the guard and Matali is the charioteer. The 4 black horses of the chariot are Tibra, Ghora, Dirghasharma and Swarnanabha. Taladhwaja’s rope is called Basuki Naga. 9 deities presiding on the ratha are Ganesh, Kartikeya, Sarbamangala, Pralambari, Hatayudha, Mrutyunjaya, Nalamvara, Mukteswar and Sheshadeva. The face of the chariot is called Ketu Bhadra and weapons associated with this particular chariot are Hala and Masula.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrasixth/tala1.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrasixth/tala1.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrasixth/tala2.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrasixth/tala2.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrasixth/tala3.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrasixth/tala3.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="some-interesting-facts-about-ratha-yatra-at-puri">Some Interesting Facts about Ratha Yatra at Puri</h2>

<ul>
  <li>Akshaya Tritiya (falls between end of April and early May) marks the start of chariot making for Ratha Yatra at Puri which takes place between end of June and early July.</li>
  <li>Ulta Ratha is the return journey of the chariots with the deities from the Gundicha Temple after eight days. This marks the end of the Ratha Yatra at Puri. This year the date of Ratha Yatra is 01.07.2022 and that of Ulto Raths is 08.07.2022.</li>
  <li>The Snan Yatra happens 14 days before ratha yatra where the deities are bathed and then for the next 14 days the temple is closed for visitors as the legend states that the deities have fever after for these days. During Nabakalebar when the deities are reconstructed (once in 8, 12 and 19 years respectively), 45 days after the Snan Yatra, Ratha Yatra takes place.</li>
  <li>The erstwhile King, Gajapati Maharaja Divyasingha Deva performs the iconic ‘Chhera Pahara’, where he cleans the three chariots with a golden broom and sandalwood-scented water before the start of the yatra. He is the chief religious functionary of the temple is the de-facto chairman of the Shri Jagannatha Temple Managing Committee. This ritual is symbolical, representing the fact that everyone is equal at the feet of the lord.</li>
  <li>There is a ritual halt of Lord Jagannath’s chariot at Salabeg’s tomb which is a reminder of universality of deity-devotee relation and that there is no divide in the eyes of God.</li>
</ul>

<figure class="half ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathraseven/fact1.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathraseven/fact1.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathraseven/fact2.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathraseven/fact2.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="puri-one-of-the-char-dhams-and-its-simbolic-ratha-yatra">Puri, One of the Char Dhams and its Simbolic Ratha Yatra</h2>

<p>You can well understand what it takes to prepare for the festival of Ratha Yatra at Puri. The day before the Ratha Yatra, the three massive chariots are brought in front of the Lion Gate (Singha Dwar) of the temple. Puri is flooded with people and humongous security forces are deployed to guard and ensure the safety of the devotees and special trains to Puri run across India. Ratha Yatra is metaphorical, it represents our life as a journey. The body is built of elements and is destroyed just as the rathas are constructed and dismantled every year. The wheels represent life as it moves on, the charioteer is the soul and the horses are the senses or consciousness. The road ‘Bada Danda’on which the chariot travels represent the road to nirvana or salvation, When our body, mind, senses and the soul are in sync, we do have a successful journey of life, a life where we attain moksha or salvation.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathraeight/art1.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathraeight/art1.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayatraeight/art2.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathraeight/art2.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathraeight/art3.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathraeight/art3.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>]]></content><author><name>Dipannita</name><email>monkatforty@gmail.com</email></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Festival" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[this is a placeholder]]></summary></entry></feed>