<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-08-16T12:14:14+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">MonkatForty</title><subtitle>My personal blog. </subtitle><author><name>Dipannita</name><email>monkatforty@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Things to do in Amritsar</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/things-to-do-in-amritsar/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Things to do in Amritsar" /><published>2022-08-14T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2022-08-14T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/things-to-do-in-amritsar</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/things-to-do-in-amritsar/"><![CDATA[<p>Amritsar is a city I want to speak of today, on the 75th Independence Day as we celebrate ‘Azadi Ka Amrit Mahotsav’. The city exudes ‘Indianness’ in every possible way; historically,geographically, socially, culturally and spiritually. As I go ahead with the list of things to do in Amritsar, slowly the reason will unfold as to why I chose to write about Amritsar today.</p>

<figure class=" ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar1/amritsar11.jpg" title="Maharaja Ranjit Singh Chowk,Amritsar">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar1/amritsar11.jpg" alt="Maharaja Ranjit Singh Chowk,Amritsar" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<p><strong>Visit the Historical Site of Jallianwala Bagh</strong> </p>

<p>Close to the Golden Temple Complex stands the Jallianwala Bagh which is a ‘memorial of national importance. At this garden the  Jallianwala Bagh Massacre   occurred on the festival of Baisakhi, on 13th April, 1919. The memory of thousand unarmed Indians- men, women and children, brutally killed and wounded by 1650 rounds of firing under the command of General Dyer still haunts one. The bullet marks are preserved and the well in which frightened people plunged in is still there. Visiting Jallianwala Bagh and the museum and gallery to honour our history, in remembrance to all those who gave their lives for the Indian freedom movement is one of the major things to do in Amritsar. There are several memorial structures, the ‘Martyr’s Memorial’ being the most significant one and more have been added with the recent renovation. The tricolour flying high here brings tears to the eyes, reminding us of the great martyrs. Ashes of Sardar Udham Singh is preserved here and the entrance has his statue too. Rabindranath Tagore renounced his knighthood in condemnation of the Jallianwala tragedy.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar2/amritsar21.jpg" title="bullet marks 1">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar2/amritsar21.jpg" alt="bullet marks 1" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar2/amritsar22.jpg" title="bullet marks 2">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar2/amritsar22.jpg" alt="bullet marks 2" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar2/amritsar23.jpg" title="bullet marks 3">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar2/amritsar23.jpg" alt="bullet marks 3" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar2/amritsar24.jpg" title="Memorial Park">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar2/amritsar24.jpg" alt="Memorial Park" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar2/amritsar25.jpg" title="New Museum">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar2/amritsar25.jpg" alt="New Museum" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar2/amritsar26.jpg" title="Amar Jyot Statue">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar2/amritsar26.jpg" alt="Amar Jyot Statue" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar2/amritsar27.jpg" title="Martyr's Memorial">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar2/amritsar27.jpg" alt="Martyr's Memorial" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar2/amritsar28.jpg" title="Jallianwala-Sardar Udham Singh">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar2/amritsar28.jpg" alt="Jallianwala-Sardar Udham Singh" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar2/amritsar29.jpg" title="Flag">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar2/amritsar29.jpg" alt="Flag" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar2/amritsar20.jpg" title="The Martyr's Well">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar2/amritsar20.jpg" alt="The Martyr's Well" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<p><strong>Visit India’s Most Popular Border, the Wagah-Attari Border</strong></p>

<p><em>Visiting the Wagah-Attari Border for the ceremonious military display by India’s Border Security Force (BSF) and Pakistan Rangers is a must in your list of</em> things to do in Amritsar. The military drills, described as ‘colourful’, is a symbol of both country’s display of brotherhood and cooperation amidst rivalry and tensions. There is a slot for the common audience to jump and rejoice and dance to the beats of patriotic songs. This ceremony is active since 1959. I found the energy and vibe of the audience amazing. Huge number of people from both the nations visit to witness this remarkable ceremony. Some civilians at that time even cross the borders with due papers and prior permission. It is a part of the ceremony. The high marches of the military personnel with legs raised as high as possible, women members of the force and the military dogs amazed me. The iron gates of both the nations open during sunset as the flags are folded marking the end of the ceremony and then the gates close with a handshake between soldiers from either side.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar3/group.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar3/group.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar3/IMG_1757.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar3/IMG_1757.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar3/IMG_1722.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar3/IMG_1722.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar3/IMG_1747.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar3/IMG_1747.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar3/IMG_1709.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar3/IMG_1709.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar3/IMG_1725.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar3/IMG_1725.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar3/IMG_1752.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar3/IMG_1752.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar3/IMG_1731.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar3/IMG_1731.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar3/IMG_1704.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar3/IMG_1704.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar3/IMG_1712.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar3/IMG_1712.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar3/IMG_1707.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar3/IMG_1707.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<p><strong>Visit the Golden Temple</strong></p>

<p><em>Golden Temple is the first thing that comes to mind when we speak of Amritsar. Visiting the Golden Temple is the most important of all the</em> things to do in Amritsar. It is a Gurdwara called ‘Harmandir Sahib or Durbar Sahib’, the most prominent spiritual site of the Sikhs. This temple is at the heart of the city and it is beyond narrow shackles of religion. One must visit this to see the alluring beauty of the temple; the dazzling gold tomb, the holy pool and the sparkling white marble. There’s no speck of dust and this temple is an epitome of community service where people are serving other people. It houses one of world’s largest kitchens, the langar. Free vegetarian meals are cooked in this community kitchen and served to thousands of visitors and devotees daily without any discrimination. Neither your faith nor your bank balance play a role here. One must have the prasad from the langar; it is blissful and tasty. Kara Prasad (ghee laden halwa) should not be missed too. One must visit the temple complex at least twice, once in the morning and once in the evening. In the evening I found the Golden Temple breath-taking. Visiting the temple soothes the mind, body and soul.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar4/amritsar41.jpg" title="Langar Cooking">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar4/amritsar41.jpg" alt="Langar Cooking" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar4/amritsar42.jpg" title="Langar">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar4/amritsar42.jpg" alt="Langar" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar4/amritsar43.jpg" title="kadha Prasad">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar4/amritsar43.jpg" alt="kadha Prasad" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar4/IMG_1777.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar4/IMG_1777.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar4/iMG.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar4/iMG.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar4/IMG_1771.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar4/IMG_1771.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar4/IMG_1802.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar4/IMG_1802.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar4/IMG_1776.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar4/IMG_1776.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar4/IMG_1774.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar4/IMG_1774.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar4/IMG_1770.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar4/IMG_1770.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar4/IMG_1769.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar4/IMG_1769.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<p><strong>Eat Amritsari Delicacies</strong></p>

<p>When you eat at Amritsar, you must go absolutely desi with your taste buds. Amritsari kulcha with chholey and a generous dollop of butter, Amritsari machhi, tikkas, kebabs and tandooris, lassi and kulfi are the ones you just can’t leave out. Even milk tea at Amritsar is special and don’t miss ‘aam papad’. Eating out is among the most significant things to do in Amritsar as this city is a pilgrimage for foodies. The taste buds will enjoy the plethora of Indian spices.</p>

<figure class="half ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar5/amritsar51.jpg" title="Amritsari Kulcha">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar5/amritsar51.jpg" alt="Amritsari Kulcha" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar5/amritsar52.jpg" title="Lassi">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar5/amritsar52.jpg" alt="Lassi" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<p><strong>Don’t Miss Shopping at Amritsar</strong></p>

<p>Don’t think twice about shopping at Amritsar. Markets in Amritsar is every girl’s favourite when it comes to ethnics like phulkaris, juttis, gorgeous jewellery and clutches and bags. Phulkari is Punjab’s traditional embroidery and carries the GI (Geographical Indications) tag. One can explore from budget friendly items to extremely lush and expensive items here. So exploring the markets in Amritsar is one of the major things to do in Amritsar.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar6/amritsar61.jpg" title="Phulkari">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar6/amritsar61.jpg" alt="Phulkari" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar6/amritsar62.jpg" title="Juttis">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar6/amritsar62.jpg" alt="Juttis" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar6/amritsar63.jpg" title="Jo bole so nihal">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar6/amritsar63.jpg" alt="Jo bole so nihal" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<p><strong>Explore Folk Arts at Amritsar</strong></p>

<p>Folk dances like Giddha and Bhangra are world famous because of their rhythm, energy and vivid dressing up. These dances are not only entertaining but represent scenes from daily life of a local. Then there is Gatka, a form of martial art presented very rhythmically. These folk dances and music are so indigenous, representing India at the very core.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar7/amritsar71.jpg" title="Bhangra">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar7/amritsar71.jpg" alt="Bhangra" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar7/amritsar72.jpg" title="Gatka">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar7/amritsar72.jpg" alt="Gatka" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar7/amritsar73.jpg" title="Gatka">
          <img src="/assets/album/amritsar/amritsar7/amritsar73.jpg" alt="Gatka" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<p><strong>Azadi Ka Amrit Mahotsav and Amritsar</strong></p>

<p>So now you definitely know why I chose to speak of Amritsar today on ‘Azadi Ka Amrit Mahotsav’. Everything about the city; its history, geography, art and culture; is extraordinarily original; extraordinarily Indian.</p>]]></content><author><name>Dipannita</name><email>monkatforty@gmail.com</email></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Travel" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Travel]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">World Peace Pagodas in India</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/world-peace-pagodas-in-India/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="World Peace Pagodas in India" /><published>2022-08-06T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2022-08-06T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/world-peace-pagodas-in-India</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/world-peace-pagodas-in-India/"><![CDATA[<p>In 1947, Japanese Buddhist Monk, Nichidatsu Fuji, the founder of Nipponzan Myohoji, a Neo-Buddhist Organisation devised the plan of constructing Peace Pagodas all over the world. He was highly influenced by Mahatma Gandhi. The pagodas were means of promoting peace and also a way of honouring and remembering those who died and suffered in the atomic attacks on Hiroshima and Nagasaki. Today there are 7 World Peace Pagodas in India out of the total 80 Peace Pagodas spread across the globe. Today, on Hiroshima Day, let’s have a quick look at the Peace Pagodas in India.They are also called Vishwa Shanti Stupas in India.</p>

<figure class="half ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/pagoda/pagoda1/peace11.jpg" title="Looking forward to Peace">
          <img src="/assets/album/pagoda/pagoda1/peace11.jpg" alt="Looking forward to Peace" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/pagoda/pagoda1/peace12.jpg" title="Shanti Stupa">
          <img src="/assets/album/pagoda/pagoda1/peace12.jpg" alt="Shanti Stupa" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="what-is-hiroshima-day">What is Hiroshima Day?</h2>

<p>6th of August is observed as Hiroshima Day every year in remembrance of the atomic bombing during Second World War, on two cities of Japan: Hiroshima and Nagasaki. Japanese cities of Hiroshima and Nagasaki was detonated on 6th and 9th August 1945, respectively. The nuclear bomb blasts killed nearly 80,000 people while more than 35,000 were injured, and generations were affected. Not only this, but it also led to massive structural damage. That is why World Peace Pagodas in India and around the world besides promoting peace, clearly declares and demands ‘no atomic wars.’</p>

<figure class=" ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/pagoda/pagoda2/peace21.jpg" title="No Nuclear Weapons">
          <img src="/assets/album/pagoda/pagoda2/peace21.jpg" alt="No Nuclear Weapons" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="seven-world-peace-pagodas-in-india">Seven World Peace Pagodas in India</h2>

<p>The 7 World Peace Pagodas in India look similar. They are majestic white domed stupas with statues of Buddha mounted on four sides. The stupas have a garden and a monastery or Buddhist temple attached to them. The first Vishwa Shanti Stupa in India was built in 1969 at the hill top of Ratnagiri Hill, at Rajgir, a town in Nalanda District of Bihar. In 1972 the Dhauli Giri Shanti Stupa (Peace Pagoda) was built at Bhubaneswar, Orissa near an ancient site of Buddhist and Shaiva significance. Darjeeling’s Peace Pagoda’s foundation was laid in 1972 and was finally inaugurated in 1992. In 1985, His Holiness, the 14 th Dalai Lama inaugurated the Peace Pagoda at Leh, Ladakh. Vishali is one of the most revered sites for Buddhists and is declared ‘protected’ by Archaeological Survey of India (ASI), as it has the Buddha Relic Stupa. It enshrines the holy ashes of Lord Buddha. A World Peace Pagoda was built at Vaishali too and was inaugurated in 1996. Wardha,Maharashtra, also has a Shanti Stupa, inaugurated in 1996. The Peace Pagoda at Indraprastha Park, Delhi, is a recent one, inaugurated in 2007.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/pagoda/pagoda3/peace31.jpg" title="Buddha carvings">
          <img src="/assets/album/pagoda/pagoda3/peace31.jpg" alt="Buddha carvings" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/pagoda/pagoda3/peace32.jpg" title="Peace pillars">
          <img src="/assets/album/pagoda/pagoda3/peace32.jpg" alt="Peace Pillars" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/pagoda/pagoda3/peace33.jpg" title="Buddha statues">
          <img src="/assets/album/pagoda/pagoda3/peace33.jpg" alt="Buddha statues" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/pagoda/pagoda3/peace34.jpg" title="Buddha statue">
          <img src="/assets/album/pagoda/pagoda3/peace34.jpg" alt="Buddha statue" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/pagoda/pagoda3/peace35.jpg" title="Peace Pagoda">
          <img src="/assets/album/pagoda/pagoda3/peace35.jpg" alt="Peace Pagoda" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="world-peace-pagodas-i-visited">World Peace Pagodas I visited</h2>

<p>Out of the 7 World Peace Pagodas in India, I had been fortunate enough to visit 5. The first one I visited was the Peace Pagoda in Darjeeling. It was 1993 when I first visited this stupa and I instantly fell in love with the calm and serenity of the place. Almost every year I visit Darjeeling and I also visit the Peace Pagoda. Perched on a slopes of Jalapar Hill, amidst pines and deodars, this place is a gem, exuberating peace and calmness. I have also visited the Shanti Stupa at Leh, a major spot at Leh. The
white domed monument is situated on a rugged hill top from where the Leh town and Shey Palace can be seen. This place reflects tranquillity. I paid a quick visit to the Shanti Stupas at Delhi and
Bhubaneswar during work tours. Once you experience the quietude and harmony of the Shanti Stupas, it helps in soothing the mind in any situation. I had also visited the first of the World Peace Pagodas in India. Visiting the Peace Pagoda in Rajgir is an experience. We reached the monastery by riding the open cable car which is an uncovered single chair ropeway. The view from the hill top is blissful.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/pagoda/pagoda4/peace41.jpg" title="Shanti Stupa at Rajgir">
          <img src="/assets/album/pagoda/pagoda4/peace41.jpg" alt="Shanti Stupa at Rajgir" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/pagoda/pagoda4/peace42.jpg" title="Darjeeling Monastery">
          <img src="/assets/album/pagoda/pagoda4/peace42.jpg" alt="Darjeeling Monastery" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/pagoda/pagoda4/peace43.jpg" title="Darjeeling Peace Pagoda">
          <img src="/assets/album/pagoda/pagoda4/peace43.jpg" alt="Darjeeling Peace Pagoda" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/pagoda/pagoda4/peace44.jpg" title="Monastery at Darjeeling Peace Pagoda">
          <img src="/assets/album/pagoda/pagoda4/peace44.jpg" alt="Monastery at Darjeeling Peace Pagoda" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/pagoda/pagoda4/peace45.jpg" title="Rajgir ropeway">
          <img src="/assets/album/pagoda/pagoda4/peace45.jpg" alt="Rajgir ropeway" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/pagoda/pagoda4/peace46.jpg" title="Leh">
          <img src="/assets/album/pagoda/pagoda4/peace46.jpg" alt="Leh" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/pagoda/pagoda4/peace47.jpg" title="Leh Peace Pagoda">
          <img src="/assets/album/pagoda/pagoda4/peace47.jpg" alt="Leh Peace Pagoda" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="world-peace">World Peace</h2>

<p>World Peace is possible when everyone is at peace with each other and with the self. It is a goal for which we all need to work hand in hand. Let us be a little more compassionate and loving and learn
to forgive and forget because as Mahatma Gandhi said, “An eye for an eye ends up making the whole world blind”.</p>]]></content><author><name>Dipannita</name><email>monkatforty@gmail.com</email></author><category term="blog" /><category term="philosophy" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Philosophy]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hemis Monastery of Ladakh and the Hemis Festival</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/hemis-monatery-of-ladakh-and-the-hemis-festival/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hemis Monastery of Ladakh and the Hemis Festival" /><published>2022-07-06T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2022-07-06T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/hemis-monatery-of-ladakh-and-the-hemis-festival</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/hemis-monatery-of-ladakh-and-the-hemis-festival/"><![CDATA[<p>Hemis Monatery of Ladakh is the largest and the richest monastery of the Ladakh region. 45 milometers from Leh, stands this famous gompa or monastery at the Hemis Village, near the Hemis National Park where the endangered snow leopards are found. This 40 kilometres drive is something that remains etched in the memory for a very long time. This 11th century monastery of Drukpa Kagyu lineage (Red Hat Sect of Buddhism) was restored in 1672 AD by Taktsang Respa Ngawang Gyatso under the patronage of the Ladakhi King, Sengge Namgyal. A golden Buddha seated on a hill top overlooks the vast expanse of the valley and the sprawling monastery. This Himalayan Tibetan-Buddhist Monastery, perched at an altitude of 12000 feet is globally famous for the Hemis Festival in June-July. In 2022, i.e.,this year the dates are 8th and 9th of July.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6957.jpg" title="Drive from Hemis to Leh">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6957.jpg" alt="Drive from Hemis to Leh" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6975.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6975.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6959.jpg" title="Hemis">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6959.jpg" alt="Hemis" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6963.jpg" title="Entrance to the Courtyard">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6963.jpg" alt="Entrance to the courtyard" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6976.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6976.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6965.jpg" title="Hemis Gompa">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6965.jpg" alt="Hemis Gompa" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6964.jpg" title="Courtyard">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6964.jpg" alt="Courtyard" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6977.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6977.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6958.jpg" title="Road to Hemis">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6958.jpg" alt="Road to Hemis" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="things-to-see-at-hemis-monastery-of-ladakh">Things to See at Hemis Monastery of Ladakh:</h2>

<p>Hemis Monastery of Ladakh has a typical Tibetan architecture where ample use of mud, wood and stones for construction is observed. Walls of the gompa have detailed murals of Tibetan gods and goddesses and other sacred symbols significant to Tibetan Tantric Buddhism. ‘Wheel of Life’ is an important painting. These paintings are extremely colourful and the colourful prayer flags compliment them and there are numerous prayer wheels of various sizes too. The vivid colours look beautiful in contrast to the rugged mountains or landscape around. A large courtyard is at the center and to its right from the entrance is Tshogs-khang, the main temple of the Buddha housing a huge gilded blue haired idol of Sakyamuni Buddha. The Du-Khang, another part of the temple, is the main Assembly Hall with the throne of the Rinpoche and the seats for the lamas (monks). There is temple dedicated to Guru Padmasambhaba and the founder of the Hemis Monastery of Ladakh. The Hemis Museum, the mural gallery and a souvenir shop are must visit sites within the gompa. The museum exhibits items, sculptures, paintings, manuscripts and thangkas which are as old as thousand years. The mural gallery has wall paintings done with stone and natural dyes. Do not miss the roof top because the panoramic view from the terrace is breath taking. Try out Tibetan dishes at the café just outside the monastery; they are delicious. The visiting time is 8 am to 6 pm and 1 pm-2 pm is lunch hour. Ticket cost per person for entry is Rs.50 and it includes a visit to the museum as well.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6969.jpg" title="Staircase to the entrance/courtyard">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6969.jpg" alt="Staircase to the entrance/courtyard" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6968.jpg" title="view from the terrace">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6968.jpg" alt="view from the terrace" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6966.jpg" title="Guru Padmasambhava">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6966.jpg" alt="Guru Padmasambhava" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6970.jpg" title="A Monk with cymbals at the mural gallery">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6970.jpg" alt="A Monk with cymbals at the mural gallery" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6961.jpg" title="Lama's stay">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6961.jpg" alt="Lama's stay" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6967.jpg" title="Terrace">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6967.jpg" alt="Terrace" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6971.jpg" title="Hemis Gompa courtyard">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6971.jpg" alt="Hemis Gompa courtyard" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6972.jpg" title="Prayer wheel">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6972.jpg" alt="Prayer wheel" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="hemis-festival-at-hemis-monastery-of-ladakh">Hemis Festival at Hemis Monastery of Ladakh</h2>

<p>Hemis Monastery of Ladakh boasts of the famous Hemis Festival which takes place in June or July (10th and 11th day of the fifth month of Tibetan Lunar calendar), to commemorate the birth anniversary of Guru Padmasambhava or Rinpoche. The festival is unique and colourful and is celebrated with tremendous devotion and spiritual fervor. The festival begins with rituals are performed by the chief monk in association with other monks. A 350 years old huge (20 feet) thangka with image of Guru Rinpoche is hung from top for the devotees. Mask dances called Chham, performed by the monks at the courtyard make the festival so distinctive and special. The dances mostly imply ‘the holy’ driving away ‘the unholy’. Ritualistic chants, beating of drums, clashing of cymbals and wailing of conchs and Tibetan horn pipes (dughchen-trumpets) create a magical environment of festivity and transcendental energy.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisthird/silk.jpg" title="Thangka of Guru Padmasambhava">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisthird/silk.jpg" alt="Thangka of Guru Padmasambhava" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisthird/Md2.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisthird/Md2.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisthird/Hemis-Festival_1.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisthird/Hemis-Festival_1.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisthird/festival.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisthird/festival.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisthird/trumpets-1.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisthird/trumpets-1.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="the-mask-dances-of-hemis-festival">The Mask Dances of Hemis Festival</h2>

<p>The mask dances of Hemis Festival is the chief attraction and follow a sequence with each dance representing a story. The audience at Hemis Monastery of Ladakh is not restricted to Buddhists only. From all across the globe keen visitors come to attend the festival; devotees, travelers, photographers and film makers.</p>

<ul>
  <li>The series of dances begin with the dance of the 4 Gomas or Gatekeepers who wear vibrant brocade dresses and huge wooden masks with skulls on top. Their dance is meant to bind the evil spirits so that they cannot escape.</li>
  <li>Next come the 12 Zhings or Dharmapalas, the guardians of the truth who dance to keep the teachings of the Buddha protected from impurities.</li>
  <li>The dance of the 5 Chemchog Heruka follows next. They represent the fierce form of Guru Rinpoche/ Padmasambhava who eliminates evil with wrath and liberate the land from darkness.</li>
  <li>Then follows the dance of the 4 Lords of the Graveyards who celebrate the death of immorality. They rejoice to celebrate the triumph of good over evil. They wear large wooden masks which look like skulls and their attires also have skeleton woven on them.</li>
  <li>The dance festival ends with the Black Hat Dance by 13 monks. They close the dance with a ritual of protecting the sacred arena such that evil can’t pervade.</li>
</ul>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfourth/mask-dance-2.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfourth/mask-dance-2.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfourth/MD.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfourth/MD.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfourth/festival-ladakh.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfourth/festival-ladakh.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfourth/mask-dance.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfourth/mask-dance.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="takeaways-from-the-hemis-festival-andor-hemis-monastery">Takeaways from the Hemis Festival and/or Hemis Monastery</h2>

<p>The pivotal point across which the majestic Hemis Monastery of Ladakh and the iconic Hemis Festival revolve is the idea of victory of good over evil. Whether we experience the enthusiasm and energy of the festival or the tranquility and solitude of the monastery during other times, we come out a changed person; a person who can retrospect, differentiate and finally choose between what is right and what is wrong. Buddha said, “By oneself, indeed, is evil done; by oneself is one defiled. By oneself is evil left undone; by oneself, indeed, is one purified. Purity and impurity depend on oneself. No one purifies another.”</p>

<figure class=" ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfive/IMG_6962-1.jpg" title="Monks Rehearsing for The Hemis Festival Mask Dance">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfive/IMG_6962-1.jpg" alt="Monks Rehearsing for The Hemis Festival Mask Dance" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>]]></content><author><name>Dipannita</name><email>monkatforty@gmail.com</email></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Festival" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Festival]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Rathas/Chariots of Jagannath’s Chariot Parade/ Ratha Yatra at Puri</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/ratha-yatra-at-puri/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Rathas/Chariots of Jagannath’s Chariot Parade/ Ratha Yatra at Puri" /><published>2022-07-01T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2022-07-01T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/ratha-yatra-at-puri</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/ratha-yatra-at-puri/"><![CDATA[<p>The word ‘Juggernaut’, meaning a large and heavy vehicle and also a huge, powerful, and overwhelming force, was coined in by the British when they saw the Chariot Parade or Rath Yatra at Puri, a beach town in Odisha. This festival is unfathomably grand, with millions of devotees visiting Puri from all across the globe. ‘Yatra’ means pilgrimage; during Ratha Yatra pilgrims flood in to see the travelling god. Lord Jagannath travels every year with his sister, Subhadra, and brother, Balabhadra, to his aunt’s house at the neighbouring Gundicha Temple, 3 kms from their residence, the famous Jagannath Temple of Puri. Each deity has their respective chariots which are brightly coloured and majestic. These chariots are built every year and the process starts from more than 2 months before the festival. This is a festival where faith, mythology, legends, craftsmanship, art and culture merge.</p>

<figure class="half ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrafirst/ratha1.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrafirst/ratha1.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrafirst/ratha2.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrafirst/ratha2.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="wood-for-chariot-making-of-rath-yatra-at-puri">Wood for Chariot Making of Rath Yatra at Puri</h2>

<p>Every year the Odisha government supplies the wood for the chariots to the temple authorities free of cost. More than 1000 logs of of Phasi, Dhaura (<em>Anogeissus latifolia</em>), Asan (<em>Terminalia elliptica</em>) and Simal (<em>Bombax ceiba</em>), along with a few other trees (12 species) are majorly used for the construction of chariots of Jagannath, Balabhadra and Subhadra every year. This year loads of logs are donated to the temple committee by private land owners of Nayagarh and Khordha Districts of Odisha.</p>

<p>After the festival of Ratha Yatra at Puri, the chariots are dismantled and the wood goes to the temple’s mega kitchen, to be used as firewood to cook <em>prasad</em> for the deities. The mega kitchen provides Prasad/bhog to at least 30,000 devotees daily. 6 times 56 types of bhog is offered to Lord Jagannath and there are more than 500 cooks for that.</p>

<figure class="half ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrasecond/wood1.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrasecond/wood1.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrasecond/wood2.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrasecond/wood2.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="the-world-famous-chariots-of-puri">The World Famous Chariots of Puri</h2>

<p>Three chariots each for the three deities are constructed every year in the same traditional pattern, without any written documented instructions. Instructions have been handed over orally for generations to the carpenters, blacksmiths, artisans, craftsmen, painters and tailors. These chariots are more than 40 feet high and the artisans begin with their gigantic wheels with a diameter of 7 feet. A total of 42 wheels are constructed. The rathas are <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deula">deula</a>-shaped, inspired by the Odisha temple architecture. Their and frames have paintings and carvings inspired by ancient Odisha Temple art and architecture too. They are also covered with vibrant fabrics with intricate Odisha embroideries. In front of the chariots are wooden statues of charioteers and horses and the devotees pull the holy ropes tied to the chariots. They are literally no ordinary ropes. Each rope is 220 feet long and has a circumference of 8 inches. Odisha Cooperative Coir Corporation (OCCC) supplies these ropes to the Shree Jagannath Temple Administration (SJTA). The astonishing fact about chariots of Ratha Yatra at Puri is that every element of each chariot is specific to that particular chariot only.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot1.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot1.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot2.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot2.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot3.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot3.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot4.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot4.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot5.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot5.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot6.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot6.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot7.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot7.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot8.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot8.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot9.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot9.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot10.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot10.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot11.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrathird/chariot11.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
    <figcaption>The Making of the Chariots
</figcaption>
  
</figure>

<h2 id="nandighosha-the-chariot-of-lord-jagannath">Nandighosha, the Chariot of Lord Jagannath</h2>

<p>Nandighosha, the Ratha of Lord Jagannath is also called Garudadhwaja and/or Kapidhwaja. It is almost 45 feet high and 35 feet wide, covered in vibrant red and yellow fabrics. The flag on top is called Trailakyamohini. The deity of Lord Jagannath is brought out of the temple by the priests with a left to right swing. The Jagannath ratha has 16 wheels. Garuda is the guard and Daruka is the charioteer and there are 4 white horses of the chariot; Sankha, Balahaka, Suweta and Haridashwa. Nandighosha’s rope is called Sankhachuda Naguni. The 9 deities carved on the ratha are Varaha, Gobardhana, Gopi Krishna, Nrishingha, Rama, Narayana, Trivikrama, Hanuman and Rudra. The face of the chariot is called Nandi Mukha and weapons associated with this particular chariot are Sankha and Chakra, those of Lord Vishnu. Vishnu is also worshiped as Lord Jagannath, the Lord of the Universe and Puri Dham is one of the Char Dhams. Understanding Ratha Yatra at Puri is incomplete without detailed knowledge of the rathas where every element of design is distinct and specific to each ratha.</p>

<figure class="half ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrafourth/nandighosha1.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrafourth/nandighosha1.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrafourth/nandighosha2.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrafourth/nandighosha2.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="padmadhwaja-the-chariot-of-lord-jagannaths-sister-subhadra">Padmadhwaja, the Chariot of Lord Jagannath’s Sister, Subhadra</h2>

<p>Subhadra’s Ratha is also called Darpadalana and/or Devadalana and is almost 42 feet high and 31 feet wide, covered in vibrant red and black fabrics. The flag on top is called Nadambika. The deity of Subhadra is brought out of the temple by the priests with out swinging, almost in a sleeping position.This ratha has 12 wheels. Jayadurga is the guard and Arjuna is the charioteer and there are 4 brown horses of the chariot; Rochika, Mochika, Jita and Aparajita. The rope of this Ratha is called Swarnachuda Naguni. 9 female deities are carved on the ratha; Chandi, Chamunda, Ugra Tara, Vana Durga, Shuli Durga, Varahi, Shyama Kali, Mangala and Vimala. Subhadra’s ratha stands in between the rathas of her brothers during Ratha Yatra at Puri. The face of the chariot is known as Bhakti Sumedha and Padma and Kalhar are the associated weapons.</p>

<figure class="half ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrafifth/subhadras1.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrafifth/subhadras1.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrafifth/subhadras2.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrafifth/subhadras2.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="taladhwaja-the-chariot-of-lord-jagannaths-brother-balabhadra">Taladhwaja, the Chariot of Lord Jagannath’s Brother, Balabhadra</h2>

<p>Balabhadra’s Ratha is called Taladhwaja and is almost 43 feet tall and 33 feet wide, covered in vibrant red and green fabrics with Unnani, the flag on. The deity of Balabhadra is brought out of the temple by the priests with a front to back swing.This ratha has 14 wheels. Basudev is the guard and Matali is the charioteer. The 4 black horses of the chariot are Tibra, Ghora, Dirghasharma and Swarnanabha. Taladhwaja’s rope is called Basuki Naga. 9 deities presiding on the ratha are Ganesh, Kartikeya, Sarbamangala, Pralambari, Hatayudha, Mrutyunjaya, Nalamvara, Mukteswar and Sheshadeva. The face of the chariot is called Ketu Bhadra and weapons associated with this particular chariot are Hala and Masula.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrasixth/tala1.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrasixth/tala1.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrasixth/tala2.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrasixth/tala2.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrasixth/tala3.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathrasixth/tala3.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="some-interesting-facts-about-ratha-yatra-at-puri">Some Interesting Facts about Ratha Yatra at Puri</h2>

<ul>
  <li>Akshaya Tritiya (falls between end of April and early May) marks the start of chariot making for Ratha Yatra at Puri which takes place between end of June and early July.</li>
  <li>Ulta Ratha is the return journey of the chariots with the deities from the Gundicha Temple after eight days. This marks the end of the Ratha Yatra at Puri. This year the date of Ratha Yatra is 01.07.2022 and that of Ulto Raths is 08.07.2022.</li>
  <li>The Snan Yatra happens 14 days before ratha yatra where the deities are bathed and then for the next 14 days the temple is closed for visitors as the legend states that the deities have fever after for these days. During Nabakalebar when the deities are reconstructed (once in 8, 12 and 19 years respectively), 45 days after the Snan Yatra, Ratha Yatra takes place.</li>
  <li>The erstwhile King, Gajapati Maharaja Divyasingha Deva performs the iconic ‘Chhera Pahara’, where he cleans the three chariots with a golden broom and sandalwood-scented water before the start of the yatra. He is the chief religious functionary of the temple is the de-facto chairman of the Shri Jagannatha Temple Managing Committee. This ritual is symbolical, representing the fact that everyone is equal at the feet of the lord.</li>
  <li>There is a ritual halt of Lord Jagannath’s chariot at Salabeg’s tomb which is a reminder of universality of deity-devotee relation and that there is no divide in the eyes of God.</li>
</ul>

<figure class="half ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathraseven/fact1.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathraseven/fact1.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathraseven/fact2.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathraseven/fact2.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="puri-one-of-the-char-dhams-and-its-simbolic-ratha-yatra">Puri, One of the Char Dhams and its Simbolic Ratha Yatra</h2>

<p>You can well understand what it takes to prepare for the festival of Ratha Yatra at Puri. The day before the Ratha Yatra, the three massive chariots are brought in front of the Lion Gate (Singha Dwar) of the temple. Puri is flooded with people and humongous security forces are deployed to guard and ensure the safety of the devotees and special trains to Puri run across India. Ratha Yatra is metaphorical, it represents our life as a journey. The body is built of elements and is destroyed just as the rathas are constructed and dismantled every year. The wheels represent life as it moves on, the charioteer is the soul and the horses are the senses or consciousness. The road ‘Bada Danda’on which the chariot travels represent the road to nirvana or salvation, When our body, mind, senses and the soul are in sync, we do have a successful journey of life, a life where we attain moksha or salvation.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathraeight/art1.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathraeight/art1.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayatraeight/art2.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathraeight/art2.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathraeight/art3.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/rathayatra/rathayathraeight/art3.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>]]></content><author><name>Dipannita</name><email>monkatforty@gmail.com</email></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Festival" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Festival]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Trip to Sittong, an Offbeat Destination</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/trip-to-sittong-an-offbeat-destination-northbengal-himalayan-hamlet/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Trip to Sittong, an Offbeat Destination" /><published>2022-03-29T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2022-03-29T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/trip-to-sittong-an-offbeat-destination-northbengal-himalayan-hamlet</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/trip-to-sittong-an-offbeat-destination-northbengal-himalayan-hamlet/"><![CDATA[<p>This Holi I made a trip to Sittong, an Offbeat Destination near Darjeeling, with my Mom. Just a long weekend (3 days) was enough. Yet during such a short trip we enjoyed almost all the things to see in Sittong, soaking into the unadulterated nature’s bliss. Haven’t you heard of Sittong? It is a cluster of small villages called Sittong Khasmahal, at 4000 to 4500 feet, located in Kurseong Subdivision of Darjeeling District. Sittong is known for its oranges, tea, cinchona and natural brooms called ‘phuljharu’ in Bengali, besides pristine natural beauty of the Eastern Himalayas.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong1/sit11.jpg" title="Path">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong1/sit11.jpg" alt="Path" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong1/sit12.jpg" title="Phooljaru">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong1/sit12.jpg" alt="Phooljaru" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong1/sit13.jpg" title="Hills at night">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong1/sit13.jpg" alt="Hills at night" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="mahal-diram-tea-gardens">Mahal Diram Tea Gardens</h2>

<p>Tea; as is the drink, so is the site relaxing. There is a well laid pathway through lush green rolling hills. The hills are green and gorgeous with tea plantations. My mom and I sat at the seat by the edge over looking the hills and absorbing the quietude. It was foggy else on a bright clear day, one can see a lot down below, including River Teesta and Siliguri Town. Trip to Sittong is incomplete without visiting the Mahal Diram Tea Estate and there is a home stay at the tea garden.  There are a few local shops selling tea, momos, toffees and maggi.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong2/sit21.jpg" title="Tea garden">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong2/sit21.jpg" alt="Tea garden" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong2/sit22.jpg" title="Mahaldiram">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong2/sit22.jpg" alt="Mahaldiram" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong2/sit23.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong2/sit23.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong2/sit24.jpg" title="Tea estate">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong2/sit24.jpg" alt="Tea estate" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong2/sit25.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong2/sit25.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="old-buddhist-monastery">Old Buddhist Monastery</h2>

<p>The mud monastery of upper Shittong is beautiful with unparalleled serenity. When it was exactly built cannot be said exactly but some say it is 300 years old and some say it is 500 years old. It definitely is old and the art inside the quaint little monastery is priceless. The frescos are not maintained but appear inspirational even with fading colours. Speaking of colours, the place has numerous colourful prayer flags. When these flags flutter with the wind, they make such a heartwarming sound. There are three chortens and the ground is filled with wild flowers. I found the place straight out of the pages of a book of vibrant happy folktales. The monastery has statues of Padmasambhaba and Buddha. Visit to this old monastery is my best take away from the trip to Sittong.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon1.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon1.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon3.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon3.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon4.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon4.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon5.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon5.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon6.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon6.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon7.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon7.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon8.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon8.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon9.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon9.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon10.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon10.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon11.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon11.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
    <figcaption>Buddhist Monastery
</figcaption>
  
</figure>

<h2 id="namthing-pokhri">Namthing Pokhri</h2>

<p>Surrounded by Shelpu Hills lies this seasonal lake spread across 10000 square meters. The lake is rain fed; we saw it dry, the bed of the lake blanketed under the grass. Yet it was so magical. It was surrounded by thick pine forests. I took the way through the woods. As I was walking through the narrow passages between the huge pine trees I could feel a certain mystique about the place. Not only because the locals consider the space sacred, there is another reason why the periphery of the lake is a restricted area. Namthing Pokhri is the abode of Himalayan Salamanders, rare endangered species conserved under Indian Wildlife Protection Act, 1972. They are considered a close cousin of the dinosaurs. Namthing Pokri is a significant site seeing spot while taking a trip to Sittong.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong4/nam1.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong4/nam1.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong4/nam2.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong4/nam2.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong4/nam3.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong4/nam3.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
    <figcaption>Namthing Pokhri
</figcaption>
  
</figure>

<h2 id="ahal-dara-view-point-and-tagore-rock">Ahal Dara View Point and Tagore Rock</h2>

<p>On the top of Shelpu Hills, amidst cinchona plantations, is perched this picturesque view point. 360 degrees panoramic view is available and on clear days the majestic snow-capped peak of Kanchenjunga steals the show. It was really foggy when we climbed the hill top, so foggy that everything around was white. We were unlucky, we had no view. Ahal Dara is generally the most important part of a trip to Sittong. One also gets to see Kalimpong Hills and Teesta River from top on clear days. Besides cinchona, there are tea plants on the hill top. Some rocks form the shape of Rabindranath Tagore and are called, ‘Tagore Rock’. While climbing downhill we rested and had some snacks at a hill shack. A few home stays exist. We had to pay Rs.50 for car parking. If one enters without car, then per head Rs. 10 is charged.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong5/ah1.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong5/ah1.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong5/ah2.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong5/ah2.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong5/ah3.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong5/ah3.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong5/ah4.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong5/ah4.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong5/ah5.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong5/ah5.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong5/ah6.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong5/ah6.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong5/ah7.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong5/ah7.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
    <figcaption>Ahal Dara
</figcaption>
  
</figure>

<h2 id="orange-garden">Orange Garden</h2>

<p>Sittong is famous for oranges. So you can’t escape a visit to the orange gardens if you are taking a trip to Sittong. Entry fee is Rs.50 per person. The orange garden is like a vibrant picnic spot amidst numerous orange trees. It is a great feeling to see so many oranges on the branches of trees. My earnest request is that visitors must not try plucking them. On request many a times, the owner gives you freshly plucked oranges.</p>

<p>For orange garden pictures, credits to nativeplanet.com</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong5/ah1.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong5/ah1.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong5/ah2.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong5/ah2.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong5/ah3.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong5/ah3.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong5/ah4.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong5/ah4.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong5/ah5.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong5/ah5.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong5/ah6.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong5/ah6.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong5/ah7.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong5/ah7.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
    <figcaption>Orange garden
</figcaption>
  
</figure>

<h2 id="mongpu">Mongpu</h2>

<p>Mongpu, the picturesque Himalayan hamlet near Kalimpong, is a well known name to Bengalis. People visit Mongpu for Mongpu Rabindra Museum which was the house of Maitreyi Devi, the author of the famous romantic novel, ‘Na Hanyate (It Does Not Die)’. Rabindranath Tagore had spent four summers in that house on Maitreyi Devi and her husband’s invitation. ‘Mongpu te Rabindranath (Tagore by The Fire Side)’ is another popular book which is Maitreyi Devi’s memoir on Rabindranath Tagore’s stay at her place in Mongpu. This imperial bungalow belonged to Dr. Manmohan Sen, the director of the cinchona factory. Thomas Anderson of Bengal Medical Service, in charge of Calcutta Botanical Garden, introduced valuable medicinal plants, especially cinchona, in 1860s in these areas; Mongpu and Ahal Dara. This pristine environment influenced Tagore to write several pieces in this house. So the museum today exhibits a lot of his writings and things he used.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon1.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon1.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon3.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon3.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon4.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon4.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon5.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon5.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon6.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon6.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon7.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon7.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon8.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon8.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon9.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon9.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon10.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon10.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon11.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon11.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
    <figcaption>Mongpu
</figcaption>
  
</figure>

<h2 id="jogighat-bridge-and-riyang-river">Jogighat Bridge and Riyang River</h2>

<p>Mongpu must be clubbed with the trip to Sittong. Jogighat Bridge, a gorgeous 74 meter long bridge connects Mongpu and Sittong. I call it gorgeous because, the bridge has innumerable colourful prayer flags, fluttering in air. The awesome hilly River Riyang flows under the bridge, over large boulders making a soothing gurgling sound. We dipped our feet in the cold water and sat for quite some time. The bridge was inaugurated by Baba Ramdev, the yoga master. The old wooden bridge from the British era is still present but is not in a state of use.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon1.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon1.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon3.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon3.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon4.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon4.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon5.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon5.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon6.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon6.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon7.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon7.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon8.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon8.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon9.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon9.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon10.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon10.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon11.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong3/mon11.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
    <figcaption>Jogighat Bridge and Riyang river
</figcaption>
  
</figure>

<h2 id="lepcha-waterfall">Lepcha Waterfall</h2>

<p>On the way to Jogighat Bridge from Lower Sittong, there is a trekking path which leads to Lepcha Waterfall. It is a site which is not very popular in the itinerary of a trip to Sittong because it is pretty difficult to reach. Since it requires a long walk for more than half an hour on a steep, dusty, rocky, narrow, secluded path; my mom and I skipped this.</p>

<figure class=" ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/lepcha/lepcha.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/lepcha/lepcha.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="how-to-reach">How to Reach</h2>

<p>From New Jalpaiguri (NJP) or Siliguri one has to travel 31kilometers, for around 2hours to reach Sittong. On the first day of our trip to Sittong we reached Sittong via Mongpu. NJP to Mongpu is 54kilometers. It is advisable to book a car privately as Sittong is very remote. 4X4 drive is helpful as the roads are steep and not in perfect condition. We had a ‘Scorpio’ for the two of us, mom and me, for travelling comfortably.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong9/reach1.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong9/reach1.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong9/reach2.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong9/reach2.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong9/reach3.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong9/reach3.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong9/reach4.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong9/reach4.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong9/reach5.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong9/reach5.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong9/reach6.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong9/reach6.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong9/reach7.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong9/reach7.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong9/reach8.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong9/reach8.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="when-and-where-to-stay">When and Where to Stay</h2>

<p>There are many home stays all across Sittong which are unable to provide you premium luxuries but are adorned with modern amenities. The home stays are mostly family run and the locals are friendly and hospitable, serving simple yet delicious and organic food. Stay rates range from Rs. 1200 to Rs. 2500 per day per person, inclusive of bed tea, breakfast, lunch, evening snacks and dinner. In the evening, home stays arrange barbecue and bonfire on request and additional charge is levied. The staying cost is extremely pocket-friendly, cost of commuting is high. Pre booking is advisable. We booked our stay with Toryok Ryang, a homestay in the Toryok Village of Sittong. You may contact Sudan (7022315073) for rooms as well as car. It is better to avoid monsoon, else one can take a trip to Sittong at anytime of the year.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong10/stay1.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong10/stay1.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong10/stay2.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong10/stay2.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong10/stay3.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong10/stay3.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong10/stay4.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong10/stay4.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong10/stay5.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong10/stay5.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong10/stay6.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong10/stay6.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong10/stay7.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong10/stay7.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong10/stay8.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong10/stay8.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong10/stay9.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong10/stay9.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="take-away-from-the-trip-to-sittong">Take Away From the Trip to Sittong</h2>

<p>Even though our trip to Sittong was extremely short, it was a valuable break. The calm and tranquil village and the simple villagers, far from the madding crowd, were rejuvenating and refreshing. The pristine nature, wonderful flowers including rhododendrons, the birds’ songs and the fresh air influenced creativity. I filled up my travel journal or travel sketch book to my heart’s content and read nature poems. Of course I clicked numerous photos. We enjoyed the full moon in the mountains. Coming back to Kolkata with a fresh bundle of energy and joy is what makes our trip to Sittong so special.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong11/end1.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong11/end1.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong11/end2.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong11/end2.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong11/end3.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong11/end3.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong11/end4.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong11/end4.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/sittong/sittong11/end5.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/sittong/sittong11/end5.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>]]></content><author><name>Dipannita</name><email>monkatforty@gmail.com</email></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Travel" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Travel]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Growing up with ‘The Adventures of Tintin</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/growing-up-with-the-adventures-of-tintin/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Growing up with ‘The Adventures of Tintin" /><published>2022-01-10T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2022-01-10T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/growing-up-with-the-adventures-of-tintin</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/growing-up-with-the-adventures-of-tintin/"><![CDATA[<p>I can recall roaming around with Tintin comics since I just started reading. My dad started handing over his Tintin comics set to me since a very early age. I have grown up with Tintin, having read each book numerous times. I cannot figure out an idea of a life without Tintin. Hergé’s ‘The Adventures of Tintin’ is not just a set of comic books but a set of emotions to me. They are a part of my life.</p>

<figure class="half ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/tintin/tintin1/tin11.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/tintin/tintin1/tin11.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/tintin/tintin1/tin12.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/tintin/tintin1/tin12.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="the-adventures-of-tintin-a-set-of-emotions">‘The Adventures of Tintin’, a Set of Emotions</h2>

<p>Tintin is witness to my fun times, sorrows and worries. I still read ‘The Adventures of Tintin’ when I feel sad or tensed and instantly I am relieved of my worries or sorrows. When I feel extremely happy and light, I often sit with Tintin. Some of these books have witnessed my falling in love for the first time. In school, exchanging Tintin comics was a means of expressing love. Gifting Tintin books is still special to me. They are expensive too. Buying the full set for me was an achievement and I did receive a pat on my back from many Tintin fans amongst friends and family. Yes, I earned it. ‘The Adventures of Tintin’ is an a set and has always been a motivating factor.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/tintin/tintin2/tin21.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/tintin/tintin2/tin21.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/tintin/tintin2/tin22.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/tintin/tintin2/tin22.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/tintin/tintin2/tin23.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/tintin/tintin2/tin23.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="what-makes-the-adventures-of-tintin-so-popular">What Makes ‘The Adventures of Tintin’ So Popular?</h2>

<p>‘The Adventures of Tintin’ is a rage in pop culture and among intellectuals as well. Bengali urban children and teens as projected in movies of the famous director, Satyajit Ray, always had a book of Tintin in their hands. Tintin per se is not the sole reason for such popularity across the globe. The other characters add to the flavor. Besides breath taking adventures, Herge has focused on exotic locations for Tintin who originated in Belgium in 1929. And we can’t ignore the brilliant illustrations or art work. Well, I call ‘The Adventures of Tintin’ an artefact of history.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/tintin/tintin3/tin31.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/tintin/tintin3/tin31.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/tintin/tintin3/tin32.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/tintin/tintin3/tin32.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/tintin/tintin3/tin33.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/tintin/tintin3/tin33.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/tintin/tintin3/tin34.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/tintin/tintin3/tin34.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="the-supporting-characters-in-the-adventures-of-tintin">The Supporting Characters in ‘The Adventures of Tintin’</h2>

<p>Tintin is a bright 16 year old journalist with a white pet dog called Snowy. He is intelligent, just, compassionate, honest, persevering and friendly. Captain Haddock, the swearing seafarer pipe-smoking Marine Captain, who first made appearance in ‘The Crab with the Golden Claws’ (1941), becomes Tintin’s best friend and the constant buddy for every other adventure. He adds to the energy and vibe of the comics. Professor Calculus is another friend who makes his first appearance in ‘Red Rackham’s Treasure’ (1943). His hysteric behavior because of being deaf together with him being a science genius made him the central character in many of the books. He is the inventor of submarine and the rocket to the moon. Thompson and Thomson, the two similar looking funny detectives, General Alcazar, Rastapopoulos and Bianca Castafiore are characters who make ‘The Adventures of Tintin’ so popular. Then there is Nestor, Oliveira, the friendly salesman, Chang, Allan, the Indian Maharaja, little Abdulla and his father the Sheikh, Zorino and the Incas and many more.</p>

<figure class="half ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/tintin/tintin4/tin41.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/tintin/tintin4/tin41.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/tintin/tintin4/tin42.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/tintin/tintin4/tin42.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="the-adventures-and-travels">The Adventures and Travels:</h2>

<p>Tintin, Captain Haddock and Professor Calculus reached moon 16 years before Neil Armstrong, the first real man on moon. So you can imagine the range of their adventures already. They have travelled extensively to the Soviet, Sahara, Congo, Egypt, Jordan, America, Central and Latin America, Scotland, China, India and Tibet. They also take us to fictional countries like Syldavia and Borduria. ‘The Adventures of Tintin’ are stories with research and creativity well knit together. We get a feel of Politics, revolt and agitations and scams and mysteries related to fake notes, opium, petroleum and more. Tintin and team has a non totalitarian opinion, standing for the weak and needy.</p>

<figure class="half ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/tintin/tintin5/tin51.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/tintin/tintin5/tin51.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/tintin/tintin5/tin52.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/tintin/tintin5/tin52.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="life-lessons-learnt-from-the-adventures-of-tintin">Life Lessons Learnt from ‘The Adventures of Tintin’:</h2>

<p>True friendship and protecting the weak and the needy are pivotal in ‘The Adventures of Tintin’. Fighting for the truth and being just is something which I have learnt. Tintin teaches how to use presence of mind; knowledge at the appropriate time and to keep your calm. The books provide hope. It has taught me never to give up. ‘The Adventures of Tintin’ is my time machine, teleporting me to my childhood and to my dream destinations like Tibet, Scotland and Peru.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/tintin/tintin6/tin61.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/tintin/tintin6/tin61.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/tintin/tintin6/tin62.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/tintin/tintin6/tin62.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/tintin/tintin6/tin63.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/tintin/tintin6/tin63.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/tintin/tintin6/tin64.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/tintin/tintin6/tin64.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/tintin/tintin6/tin65.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/tintin/tintin6/tin65.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/tintin/tintin6/tin66.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/tintin/tintin6/tin66.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="important-fundas-from-tintincom">Important Fundas from tintin.com</h2>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/tintin/tintin7/tin71.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/tintin/tintin7/tin71.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/tintin/tintin7/tin72.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/tintin/tintin7/tin72.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/tintin/tintin7/tin73.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/tintin/tintin7/tin73.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/tintin/tintin7/tin74.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/tintin/tintin7/tin74.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/tintin/tintin7/tin75.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/tintin/tintin7/tin75.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<p>I am grateful to Georges Prosper Remi, known by the pen name Hergé for gifting us with Tintin. 10th of January, 1929, is considered the birthday of Tintin, the young 16 year old dare devil reporter, who never grows old. Happy birthday dear Tintin, you will always stay with me. Well, I call my beloved nephew, Tintin.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/tintin/tintin8/tin81.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/tintin/tintin8/tin81.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/tintin/tintin8/tin82.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/tintin/tintin8/tin82.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/tintin/tintin8/tin83.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/tintin/tintin8/tin83.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/tintin/tintin8/tin84.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/tintin/tintin8/tin84.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/tintin/tintin8/tin85.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/tintin/tintin8/tin85.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>]]></content><author><name>Dipannita</name><email>monkatforty@gmail.com</email></author><category term="blog" /><category term="books" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Books]]></summary></entry></feed>